Welcome.
欢迎。
Now that we are done with the basic climbing movement with our character, and it's about
现在我们已经完成了我们角色的基本攀爬动作，现在是时候开始固定手和脚的位置了。
time that we start to fix the hand and feet placement.
是时候我们开始修正手和脚的位置了。
And as you can see, while we are climbing, there's quite some offset between the hands
正如你所看到的，当我们在攀爬的时候，手和可攀爬的表面之间有一些偏移。
and the climbable surface.
和可攀爬的表面之间有一些偏移。
And that's what we are going to fix next, and that's something that we need to do through
这就是我们接下来要解决的问题，而这是我们需要通过
Control Rig.
控制装置。
Besides using Control Rig to adjust the animation, we can also use it to generate things like
除了用Control Rig来调整动画外，我们还可以用它来生成一些东西，例如
procedural animation, hands and legs IK, things like that.
程序性动画，手和腿的IK，诸如此类的东西。
So let's look at how we can set it up.
因此，让我们看看我们如何设置它。
I'm going to right mouse button click and go to animation, scroll down to this Control
我将按下鼠标右键，转到动画，向下滚动到这个控制
Rig.
装备。
I'm going to select this Control Rig and select this one as the parent class, click create.
我将选择这个控制钻机并选择这个作为父类，点击创建。
And I'm going to name this one CR_ClimbedIK and double click to open it.
我要把这个命名为CR_ClimbedIK，然后双击来打开它。
And here we are inside of the Control Rig editor.
现在我们在控制装置编辑器中。
Everything is pretty empty.
一切都很空。
The first thing that we need to do, we need to import the bone hierarchy that we want
我们需要做的第一件事是，我们需要导入我们想在运行时调整的骨骼层次结构。
to adjust during runtime.
在运行时进行调整。
So I'm going to go to this Rig hierarchy and I'm going to click this import hierarchy.
所以我要去这个Rig层次结构，然后点击这个导入层次结构。
And here we need to select the mesh.
在这里我们需要选择网格。
So in the drop down here, I'm going to search many simple.
所以在这里的下拉菜单中，我将搜索许多简单的。
This is the mesh that we've been using the whole time.
这就是我们一直在使用的网格。
So I'm going to select it and click OK.
所以我要选择它并点击确定。
And there you go.
然后你就可以了。
There are many in our viewport.
我们的视口里有很多。
So if you'd like to catch up with me, you can pause the video now and give this a go.
所以，如果你想跟上我的节奏，你可以暂停视频，试试这个。
Welcome back.
欢迎回来。
Now we have the bone hierarchy ready.
现在我们已经准备好了骨头的层次结构。
Next thing that we're going to look at is this forwards solve.
接下来我们要看的是这个前向解。
So this one here means we want to use the rig to control the bones and the backwards
所以，这意味着我们要用装备来控制骨骼，而反向的
solve is the exact opposite.
解则完全相反。
We want to use the bone to control the rig.
我们想用骨头来控制装备。
Now I just want to set up some simple debug lines to prove this Control Rig is working.
现在我只想设置一些简单的调试线来证明这个控制钻机是有效的。
And to do that, I'm first going to use the right mouse button click and I'm going to
要做到这一点，我首先要使用鼠标右键点击，然后我打算
type in get transform and select this node get transform.
键入get transform，然后选择这个节点get transform。
So the item type here is the bone and in the name here we can select which bone we want.
所以这里的项目类型是骨头，在这里的名称中我们可以选择我们想要的骨头。
So in the drop down here, I'm going to scroll down and I'm going to select this IK_FUL.
所以在这里的下拉菜单中，我要向下滚动并选择这个IK_FUL。
So an IK bone is a virtual bone in our characters bone hierarchy.
所以IK骨是我们的角色骨层次中的一个虚拟骨。
So in the search box here, if I search IK and select this IK_FUL, you can see this is where
所以在搜索框中，如果我搜索IK并选择IK_FUL，你可以看到这是它的位置。
it is located.
它的位置。
So I'm going to use the location of it as the starting point to draw a simple debug
所以我将使用它的位置作为起点来画一个简单的调试线
line to prove our Control Rig is working.
来证明我们的控制钻机在工作。
And to do that, it's actually something pretty similar as what we've done so far.
要做到这一点，实际上和我们到目前为止所做的事情非常相似。
So I'm going to drag out this node and click this transform and I'm going to drag out this
所以我要拖出这个节点，并点击这个变换，然后我将拖出这个
translation.
翻译。
So first I'm going to use a subtract now.
首先，我将使用一个减法。
And the value that I'm going to subtract from it.
而我要从中减去的值。
So to our bones, the forward axis is this y axis.
所以对我们的骨头来说，前进轴是这个Y轴。
So I'm going to give it a value of 10 units for the y.
所以我将给它一个10个单位的Y轴值。
So our trace start will be behind this IK bone.
所以我们的追踪起点将在这个IK骨骼的后面。
And I'm going to use another node add.
我将使用另一个节点添加。
So this is going to be our trace end.
所以这将是我们的追踪终点。
And I'm going to give it a value of 100 units for the y.
我将给它一个100单位的Y值。
All right.
好的。
So now that we have our line trace start, our line trace end, I'm going to use a debug
现在我们有了线条追踪的起点和终点，我将使用一个调试
function to show it.
函数来显示它。
So right mouse button click and I'm going to type in draw line and select this function
所以鼠标右键点击，我将输入draw line并选择这个函数
and connect this execution pin to here.
并把这个执行引脚连接到这里。
So the socket A is our line trace start, socket B is our line trace end.
所以插座A是我们的线迹开始，插座B是我们的线迹结束。
And the color here will be red.
而这里的颜色将是红色。
That's fine.
这很好。
And I'm going to change its thickness to five units.
我将把它的厚度改为5个单位。
And you can see this is our debug line.
你可以看到这就是我们的调试线。
Maybe three units is enough.
也许三个单位就够了。
All right.
好的。
I'm going to click compile.
我将会点击编译。
And I'd also like to see this inside the file viewport.
我也想在文件视窗里看到这个。
So go back to my content browser.
所以请回到我的内容浏览器。
I'm going to double click to open my animation blueprint.
我将双击来打开我的动画蓝图。
We first need to run our control rig inside the file ABP.
我们首先需要在文件ABP里面运行我们的控制钻机。
So go back to my Anon graph.
所以回到我的Anon图。
I'm going to select this full body and drag out another pin.
我将选择这个完整的身体，并拖出另一个针。
And I'm going to type in control rig and select this node, scroll down to this control rig
我将输入控制设备并选择这个节点，向下滚动到这个控制设备
class.
类。
And in the drop down here, I'm going to select this CR_climb_myk and click compile.
在这里的下拉菜单中，我要选择CR_climb_myk，然后点击编译。
Now when we click play, this control rig will be run.
现在当我们点击播放时，这个控制装置将被运行。
All right.
好的。
Go back to my viewport.
回到我的视口。
I'm going to click play and we have an issue.
我将点击播放，我们有一个问题。
We cannot see the debug line.
我们不能看到调试线。
And the reason for that is we need to enable the debug shape for our control rig.
其原因是我们需要为我们的控制装置启用调试形状。
And that's something we need to do through console commands.
而这是我们需要通过控制台命令来做的事情。
So I'm going to press the TELTA key on my keyboard and type in a_nmnode.controlrig.debug
所以我将按下键盘上的TELTA键，输入a_nmnode.controlrig.debug
and add in space, type in 1.
并加上空格，键入1。
So this is how we can show the debug shape for our control rig.
所以这就是我们如何显示我们的控制装置的调试形状。
And hit enter.
然后按回车键。
And there you go.
然后你就可以了。
This is our debug line.
这就是我们的调试线。
Our control rig is working.
我们的控制装置正在工作。
That's great.
这很好。
Next thing I'm going to do, I'm going to go back to my Climb_MyK.
接下来我要做的是，我将回到我的Climb_MyK。
Now we have line trace start.
现在我们有了线追踪的开始。
We have line trace end.
我们有了线迹的终点。
I'm going to use this to set up some sort of trace for us to detect the surface.
我要用它来设置某种跟踪，以便我们检测表面。
And to do that, there's one function.
要做到这一点，有一个函数。
It's called severe_trace.
它叫severe_trace。
So we have two options here.
所以我们在这里有两个选项。
So we can trace by object types or by trace channel.
所以我们可以按对象类型或按跟踪通道来跟踪。
Just to be consistent with our code, I'm going to use object types in here.
为了和我们的代码保持一致，我将在这里使用对象类型。
So we need to pass in a start, an end, and the object types.
所以我们需要传入一个开始，一个结束，以及对象类型。
So I'm going to use this one as the starting point and this end for the end.
所以我打算用这个作为起点，用这个作为终点。
For the object types, this is an array.
对于对象类型，这是一个数组。
I'm going to click this button and I'm going to trace for this word static.
我将点击这个按钮，我将追踪这个词的静态。
The radius is five units.
半径是五个单位。
That's fine.
这很好。
And I'm going to draw this hit location.
我将画出这个击中的位置。
And there's another debug function that we can use.
还有一个调试函数，我们可以使用。
So it's called draw_transform.
所以它被称为draw_transform。
And connect this pin to here.
并将这个引脚连接到这里。
And click this dropdown for this transform as in this hit location.
然后点击这个下拉菜单，在这个位置进行转换。
And the mode here, I'm going to change it to box.
这里的模式，我要把它改成盒子。
So I only want to draw this box if we have a valid hit location.
所以我只想在我们有一个有效的撞击位置时画这个盒子。
And for this type of if/else condition, same as Blueprint, we can use the node branch.
而对于这种类型的如果
So I'm going to hold down B and left mouse button click to bring out the branch node,
null
connect this pin to here, and connect this hit to here.
So when this condition is true, I'm going to run this node.
null
And I'm going to click compile, hit save, then go back to my viewport, click play.
And I'm going to run to the surface here.
null
And you can see we have hit.
And this information is extremely valuable for us to do the things we want next.
null
And it's time for a challenge.
So a challenge is simple.
null
Same as I did, I'd like you to create a control rig and run it in your animation Blueprint.
So I place my control rig now before our montage slot so that the bone data it controls won't
null
mess up with the animation montages that we are using.
And once you are sure your control rig is running, same as I did, I'd like you to draw
null
a simple sphere chase with debug shapes showing on your screen.
Just in case you won't be able to see the debug shape later, you'll need to use the
null
console command and unknown.controlrig.debug and add in in space 1.
So this should help you to enable the debug shape.
null
And most importantly, get comfortable with the control rig editor.
Alright pause the video now and give this a go and I'll see you in the next lecture.
null
[Music]